Guide to the Bessborough Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Bessborough papers
1774-1827
OSB MSS 55
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.42
(1 box)
The papers include letters written to Lady Bessborough; poetry in the hands of Lady Devonshire and of Lamb; and music, two silhouettes, and one drawing. Some of the letters contain eyewitness descriptions of the Napoleonic Wars.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Bequest of James Marshall and Marie-Louise Osborn. For further information, consult the appropriate curator.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
HENRIETTA FRANCES SPENCER PONSONBY, COUNTESS OF BESSBOROUGH, 1761-1821
Henrietta Frances Spencer Ponsonby, Countess of Bessborough, was born on June 16, 1761, the younger daughter of John, Earl Spencer. In November of 1780 she married Frederick Ponsonby, viscount Duncannon; her dowry of L20,000 went toward Duncannon's L30,000 debt. Their first child, John William Ponsonby, was born on August 31, 1781. Despite their incompatibilities, and Henrietta's abortive elopement with Charles Wyndham, one of the King's friends, the couple had four children during the first seven years of their marriage; their only daughter, Caroline (later Lady Caroline Lamb), was born in 1785. Duncannon initiated divorce proceedings against his wife in 1789, prompted by her relationship with the playwright Richard Brinsley Sheridan, but was persuaded by his father and brother-in-law to withdraw the bill from the House of Lords.
While visiting Italy in 1794, Henrietta began a lengthy relationship with Lord Granville Leveson-Gower. Their first child, Harriet Stewart, was born in August of 1800 and placed with foster parents.
Henrietta and her sister, Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire, remained close throughout their lives and frequently visited and traveled together until Henrietta's death in 1806. Georgiana spent many summers in residence at Manresa House in Roehampton, when she gardened and established a hostel for "unfortunate girls." In December of 1809, Lord Granville Leveson-Gower, recently named Secretary of War in Canning's cabinet, married Georgiana's daughter, Harriet Cavendish.
In 1812, Lady Bessborough escorted her daughter to Ireland in a successful effort to end Caroline's relationship with Lord Byron. She died in retirement in Florence in November, 1821.
GEORGIANA SPENCER CAVENDISH, DUCHESS OF DEVONSHIRE, 1757-1806
Georgiana Spencer Cavendish, Duchess of Devonshire, was born on June 9, 1757, the eldest daughter of John, Earl Spencer. On June 5, 1774, she married William Cavendish, fifth Duke of Devonshire. She quickly became the hostess and center of the "Devonshire House Circle" of Whig aristocrats and a friend and partisan of Charles James Fox. She was the model for Sheridan's Lady Teazle in School for Scandal, set the fashions at court, and published The Slyph, a popular and notorious novel, anonymously in 1778. Her enthusiastic and effective canvassing in support of Fox in the hotly contested Westminster election of 1784 was widely lampooned in the popular press.
After several miscarriages, Georgiana bore the Duke three children, first two daughters and then, in 1790, a son and heir, William Cavendish, Marquis of Hartington. She was separated from the Duke in 1791 over her extravagant gambling debts and her pregnancy by Charles Grey, who had replaced the Duke of Dorset in her affections. Their daughter, Eliza Courtney, was born in February 1792 and raised by Grey's parents in Northumberland. Georgiana and her husband were reconciled, in part due to the influence of Lady Elizabeth Foster, Devonshire's mistress, and the three formed a household which included the children of both women by Devonshire.
Georgiana's health declined in the 1790s after a severe illness which affected her eyes, and she and her household lived more quietly at Devonshire and at Chatsworth, although she continued to be interested in political affairs and troubled by substantial debts. Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire died at Devonshire House on March 30, 1806. The Duke of Devonshire married Lady Elizabeth Foster on October 19, 1809, despite the opposition of all of his children; he died two years later.
LADY CAROLINE LAMB, 1785-1828
Lady Caroline Ponsonby Lamb was born November 13, 1785, the youngest daughter of Lord and Lady Bessborough. She married William Lamb, eldest son of Lord Melbourne, on June 3, 1805. Their only son William was born in August 1807.
In the spring of 1812 she met Lord Byron at Holland House. Byron was enjoying his new celebrity as the author of "Childe Harold's Pilgrimage," and the two began a four month affair, despite her opinion of him as "mad, bad, and dangerous to know." The relationship scandalized her family, and in August her mother and her husband took her to Ireland in order to end the affair. Lamb began separation proceedings, but abandoned them the following year, though the couple continued to live apart.
In 1816, she published Glenarvon, a thinly disguised retelling of her relationship with Byron in novel form. It only served to renew the gossip, and her husband sent her from London to live primarily at Brocket Hall in Hertfordshire. The novel was translated into Italian in 1817; upon hearing that Byron had laughed over it with Madame de Staël, Lamb is said to have made a bonfire of Byron letters and keepsakes on the grounds at Brocket.
She published two more novels; Graham Hamilton (1822) and Ada Reis (1823). Her separation from Lamb became final in 1825, and she spent the remainder of her life in seclusion at Brocket Hall with her father-in-law and her invalid son George. She died at Melbourne House in the presence of her husband on January 26, 1828.
Scope and Contents
The Bessborough Papers consist of correspondence and manuscripts by and connected with Henrietta, Countess of Bessborough; her sister Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire; and her daughter Lady Caroline Lamb. The papers span the dates 1774-1826 and have been organized into two series: Series I, Letters to Lady Bessborough; and Series II, Manuscripts.
Series I, Letters to Lady Bessborough, is housed in folders 1-34 and consists of single letters addressed to the Countess of Bessborough by a variety of friends and relatives. Many of the letters detail social engagements and plans for visits; some letters are described more fully in the box and folder listing. Lady Bessborough's literary interests are reflected in letters from Lady Eleanor Butler, commenting on Lady Bessborough's visit to Llangollen; from the poet Samuel Jackson Pratt; and from W. Drew, who encloses verses addressed to his patroness.
Lady Bessborough's travels on the Continent and concern for friends caught up in the events of the French Revolution are also documented in letters from the comtesse de Boufflers-Rouverel, Baron Armfelt, and the vicomte de Leon. Folder 11 contains a letter from the Duchess of Devonshire describing the seige of Mainz, and folder 12 holds letters from the Duke of Dorset to the Duchess of Devonshire on developments in France at the end of 1791. The collection also contains a letter from the Earl of Chichester on the surrender of Valenciennes and one from "le chevalier W" on the situation at Coblenz. Folders 32-34 house letters and fragments by unidentified authors on events during the Terror.
Series II, Manuscripts, is housed in folders 36-108 and is organized into two subseries: Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire and Lady Caroline Lamb. The first subseries consists of detatched album leaves upon which manuscripts in various hands have been pasted. The leaves are numbered, and as this order may reflect the original order of the album it has been preserved in the current box and folder listing. Contents include an epitaph for the Duchess, ascribed to her; occasional poems addressed to her sister and other relatives; a prayer for "my sister" which contains self-reproaches for "my pointed tongue" (folder 63); and prose fragments on subjects such as jealousy, misfortune, and self-interest. There are also several apparently contemporary poems of unknown authorship.
The second subseries, Lady Caroline Lamb, has been arranged in three sections: Poems Attributed to Lady Caroline Lamb; Other Poems; and Other Papers. The first section includes a poem that seems to be addressed to Lamb's only child ("A little Lamb there was who from its birth"); several romantic or melancholy verses; and a poem "On a Broken Guitar" accompanied by a reply poem from "Mrs. Lilburn."
There are several items which suggest or have been connected to Lamb's relationship with Lord Byron. A poem dated "April 23, 1824" which opens "And can I believe that the form I beheld" seems to be a reaction to the news of Byron's death; the poem "by those eyes whose sweet expression" has been annotated "Ldy. Caroline Lamb on Byron. 1814?" Folder 83 contains a copy of "This heart has never stoop'd its pride," which was published in a different version in Lamb's Glenarvon. An annotator attributes it, probably incorrectly, to Byron himself. A heavily corrected stanza expressing "agonizing woe" and followed by what may be the fragment of a letter is found in folder 90.
Other Poems includes copies of popular sentimental verse by L. E. L.; poems addressed to Lamb by friends; and two copies of Byron's epitaph on his dog. Other Papers, located in folders 101-106, contains silhouettes and a pencil sketch; the manuscript of an Italian "favola per Carolina mia;" and a sheet of possible chapter mottoes for an unidentified work.
Napoleonic Wars, 1800-1815 -- Personal narratives, British; Women -- Great Britain; Poetry; Bessborough, Henrietta Frances Spencer Ponsonby, Countess of, 1761-1821; Butler, Eleanor, Lady, 1739-1829; Cavendish, Georgiana Spencer, Duchess of Devonshire, 1757-1806; Dorset, John Frederick Sackville, Duke of, 1745-1799; Lamb, Caroline, Lady, 1785-1828; Pelham, Thomas, Earl of Chichester, 1756-1826; Ponsonby, John William, 1781-1847; Ponsonby, Sarah, 1755-1831; Pratt, Mr. (Samuel Jackson), 1749-1814; Ripon, Frederick John Robinson, Earl of, 1782-1859
- Letters to Lady Bessborough, Series I
  - ABERCORN, ANNE JANE GORE HAMILTON, MARCHIONESS OF, 1763-1827
    - 2 ALS to Lady Bessborough; Bognor, [ca. 1805] (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Scope and Contents
      One page has a list of popes in the handwriting of Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire.
  - AGUESSEAU, MARQUISE D'
    - AL to [Lady Bessborough]; Paris, 1813 Jan 8 (Box 1, Folder 2)
      In French
  - ARMFELT, GUSTAV MAURITZ D', BARON, 1757-1814
    - Letter (in the third person) to Lady Bessborough; Naples, 1794 Feb 3 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - AUGUSTUS FEDERICK, DUKE OF SUSSEX, 1773-1843
    - ALS to Lady Caroline Lamb, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - BATHURST, GEORGINA LENNOX BATHURST, COUNTESS, 1765-1841
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; London, [1820?] Feb 5 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - BESSBOROUGH, JOHN WILLIAM PONSONBY, EARL OF, 1781-1847
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; London, 1815 Jul 28 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - BOUFFLERS-ROUVEREL, MARIE CHARLOTTE HIPPOLYTE, [de Camps de Saujon, Comtesse de, 1725-1800]
    - ALS to Lady Duncannon (afterwards Lady Bessborough), 1791 Jul 9 (Box 1, Folder 7)
      In French.
  - BROGLIE, ALBERTINE (DE STAëL), DUCHESSE DE, 1787-
    - 2 ALS to Lady Bessborough, 1805, 1816 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - BUTLER, ELEANOR, LADY, 1739-1829
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Llangollen, 1809 Apr 22 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      On Lady Bessborough's visit and Mrs. Tighe's poetry. Written jointly with Sarah Ponsonby, in Sarah's hand.
  - [COIGNY, AUGUSTIN LOUIS JOSEPH CASIMIR GUSTAVE, 1780-1865]
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; [Paris], [1821 May] (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Offering a ticket to view a Royal procession from the Louvre. In French.
  - DEVONSHIRE, GEORGIANA (SPENCER) CAVENDISH, DUCHESS OF, 1757-1806
    - 2 ALS to Lady Bessborough, [1774?], 1793 (Box 1, Folder 11)
      [1774?] letter in French. The letter of 1793 August 6 describes the aftermath of the seige of Mainz.
  - DORSET, JOHN FREDERICK SACKVILLE, DUKE OF, 1745-1799
    - 4 AL to the Duchess of Devonshire; Knole, 1791, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - DREW, W.
    - 4 letters to Lady Bessborough; Bridgewater, 1795-1804 (Box 1, Folder 13)
      Including verses, literary comments, and reminiscences.
  - FOSCOLO, UGO, 1778-1827
    - AL to Lady Bessborough; London, 1819 Nov 13 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      Declines an invitation because of ill health. In French.
  - FRONDEVILLE, MARQUISE DE
    - ALS to [Lady Bessborough]; 15 rue de Regard., 1821 Aug 20 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - LEON, VICOMTE DE
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Brussels., [1791?] Jul 5 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - LIEVEN, DARIA KHRISTOFOROVNA BENCKENDORFF, KNIAGINIA, 1785-1857
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Tunbridge W Wells, [1812] Aug 17 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - LIQUIER, ----
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Marseilles, 1816 Apr 29 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - LYNEDOCH, THOMAS GRAHAM, BARON, 1748-1843
    - AL and ALS to Lady Bessborough, [1809?], 1821 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - MANSFIELD, FREDERICA MARKHAM MURRAY, COUNTESS OF, 1774-1860
    - AL to [Lady Bessborough?], n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - MEDNYANSZKY, BARON DE
    - AL to [Lady Bessborough]; London, 1795 May 30 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - MELBOURNE, ELIZABETH MILBANKE LAMB, VISCOUNTNESS, 1752-1818
    - AL to Lady Bessborough; [London], 1815 Jul 28 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - MERCATI, FRANCESCO
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; London, 1819 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - PELHAM, THOMAS, EARL OF CHICHESTER, 1756-1826
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Coblenz, 1793 Jul 29 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      On surrender of Valenciennes.
  - PRATT, SAMUEL JACKSON, 1749-1814
    - ALS to [Lady Bessborough]; London, 1811 Jan, Feb (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - PREEDY, JAMES, 1753-1836
    - ALS to Lord Bessborough; St. Albans, 1814 Mar 20 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - RIPON, FREDERICK JOHN ROBINSON, EARL OF, 1782-1859.
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; St. James's Street, [1809?] (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - ST. ALBANS, CATHERINE PONSONBY, DUCHESS OF, 1742-1789
    - ALS to Lady Duncannon (later Lady Bessborough); Haworth House, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - SARRAZIN, [JEAN?], GENERAL
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; London, 1813 Jul 26 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - SYDENHAM, THOMAS
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough; Curzon Street, [ca. 1794?] (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - VAUGHAN, [JOHN TAYLOR?]
    - ALS to Lady Bessborough, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - W, LE CHEVALIER
    - AL to the Duchess [of Devonshire]; Coblenz, [1791?] Sep 23 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - UNIDENTIFIED AUTHORS
    - Unidentified AL fragment. In French, [1792 Sep?] (Box 1, Folder 33)
      Report of the Princesse de Lamballe's "trial" and death, as well as of the Terror in Paris
      With 2 ALS fragments to Lady Bessborough, in French, 1821, n.d.
    - "Les prisonniers d'orlians...." Autograph manuscript, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 2 manuscript newsletters, 1793, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 35)
      Concerning troop movements and sieges during the early wars of the French Revolution One in French.
- Manuscripts, Series II
  - GEORGIANA SPENCER CAVENDISH, DUCHESS OF DEVONSHIRE
    - Album Pages
      - "Epitaph", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 36)
        Manuscript poem with corrections and additions
        Annotated: "for herself by Georgiana Couness of Devonshire"
      - "Active misfortunes can be better supported than the gloom of passive sorrows", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 37)
        Manuscript prose
      - "Jealousy is of all passions, the one which is most inexplicable to those who are not initiated", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 38)
        Manuscript prose with corrections and additions
      - "Opening. Comparison of a tree....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - "Loud was the blast....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 40)
        Manuscript prose description of "the White cliffs of Albion"
      - "We [partake?] so much in the sorrow and distress of those whom we really love..." (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - "If the feeble sentiments of self-interest....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - "Amidst those who have ....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - "To Ly Bessboro, as a proof of my progress in metaphysicks", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 44)
        Manuscript poem
      - "The doom is past....", [1802] (Box 1, Folder 45)
        Manuscript blank verse with corrections and additions
      - "With Hydrogen, Oxygen,....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 46)
        Manuscript verse fragment, corrected
      - "To you, An interval.", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - "Laura is Laura....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 48)
        Manuscript poem with corrections
      - "Resolv'd yt we'll no longer err....", 1788 Jul (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - "Tho' rude the soil, the plant too weak", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - "More than the ties of passing years", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 51)
        Manuscript poem, annotated "To the C. of Bessboro"
      - "Epilogue to de Montfort", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - "Absence", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 53)
      - "Seek not to check a tender heart...." (Box 1, Folder 54)
      - "Oh Sleep my child, benignant angels guard thee....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 55)
        - Manuscript poem with corrections, n.d.
      - "To Ly Caroline Ponsonby with a new years gift of a pencil", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 56)
      - "The Hope", 1799 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 57)
        Manuscript poem contained in note to "my Dearest love"
      - "Georgiana", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 58)
      - "On Lady D--'s Singing", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 59)
        Manuscript poem, annotated "I believe by Wm. Spencer"
      - "L'Ellesa lieve lieve....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 60)
        Manuscript poem in Italian
      - "A gentleman in Switzerland...." (Box 1, Folder 61)
        Manuscript including verse in French
      - "Spencer in Nature's fairest mould was cast....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 62)
        Manuscript poem with annotation, "Wm. Spencer"
      - "Examination", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 63)
        Manuscript prose on religious topics
      - "Guard oh Almighty god my dearest sister....", 1792 Aug 27 (Box 1, Folder 64)
        Manuscript prose fragment
      - "The Table", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 65)
        Manuscript poem With "Friday," manuscript poem
      - "Suite des Evenémens", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 66)
        Manuscript prose concerning the trial of Madame de Lamballe In French.
      - "Oh most merciful God look down and receive my prayer...." (Box 1, Folder 67)
      - "Per doni riceveuti....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 68)
        Manuscript prose In Italian
      - "Moi dont la timide tendresse...." (Box 1, Folder 69)
        Manuscript poem In French
      - "If e'er sincerity inscrib'd the stone....", 1787 May (Box 1, Folder 70)
      - Bibliographical information, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - LADY CAROLINE LAMB
    - Poems Attributed to Lady Caroline Lamb
      - "A little Lamb there was who from its birth....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 72)
        Manuscript poem Illustrated with pencil sketch With second poem on reverse, "Bright star of Faith."
      - "And can I believe that the form I beheld....", 1824 Apr 13 (Box 1, Folder 73)
        Manuscript poem With pencil note attributing crossed out lines on the page to "Byron's hand."
      - "April 1821. To M---", [1821 Apr] (Box 1, Folder 74)
      - "By those eyes whose sweet expression....", [1814?] (Box 1, Folder 75)
        Manuscript poem Pencil note: "Ldy. Caroline Lamb on Byron. 1814?"
      - "Clifton! While many seek thy purer air....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 76)
      - "For the heart that is noble and high in its nature...." (Box 1, Folder 77)
      - "My name it was once Virgil Hocklington....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 78)
        Manuscript poem, incomplete Menu in French on verso
      - "Oh, sad memorial to my care-worn mind...." (Box 1, Folder 79)
        Manuscript poem, corrected Two versions of first lines present
      - "Oh, think not that my humble Muse....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 80)
      - "Oh thou to friendship most untrue....", 1822 Jan 31 (Box 1, Folder 81)
        Manuscript poem With note in same hand, "Read these."
      - "On a Broken Guitar", 1826 (Box 1, Folder 82)
        Manuscript poem "Caro L 1826" at foot of page With "Reply by Mrs. Lilburn" on same sheet
      - "The Ring", 1809 Dec (Box 1, Folder 83)
        Manuscript poem Annotated in same hand: "December 1809 by Caroline Lamb"
      - "This heart has never stoop'd its pride...", [ca. 1814?] (Box 1, Folder 84)
        Manuscript poem Varies from the version published in Glenarvon (1816) Sheet addressed to "Ly. Caroline Lamb" Annotated in pencil: "Ld. Byron's last and unfinished lines to Lady Caroline Lamb"
      - "To every man or rich or poor....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 85)
      - "To Grandmama on Spring" (Box 1, Folder 86)
      - "What pity 'tis that nature erred....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 87)
      - "What would I give one little word to hear....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 88)
      - "When with generous ardour burning...", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 89)
        Manuscript poem With variant text: "When with softer passions burning" in a different hand
      - "Written Underneath a very beautiful design...." (Box 1, Folder 90)
        Manuscript poem, "I am alone"
      - "...my heart the agonizing woe...", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 91)
        Manuscript stanza, heavily corrected and crossed out Followed by: "I have no reproaches to make you no not one---but" Greek vocabulary exercises on verso
    - Other Poems
      - "Answer to Lady C.L.'s Beautiful Lines on Herself", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 92)
      - "Elegy", [ca. 1806] (Box 1, Folder 93)
        Manuscript poem On the death of Georgiana, Duchess of Devonshire
      - "I saw thee, rose, in all thy pride...", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 94)
      - "Lines Extracted from Miss. L.E.L.'s beautiful poem of The Improvisatrice, [ca. 1825] (Box 1, Folder 95)
        Manuscript of selections from L. E. L. (Leticia Elizabeth Landon)
      - "Sacred to the Memory of the Honorable Countess Dowager Spencer", 1814 Mar (Box 1, Folder 96)
      - "The Spartan Mother near the Dead Body of Her Son", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 97)
        Manuscript poem With "A Portrait" in the same hand
      - "To Lady Caroline Lamb", 1825 Oct 18 (Box 1, Folder 98)
        Manuscript poem Postmarked "18 Oc 1825"
      - "To own M., 4 minutes after the event", 1811 Sep 21 (Box 1, Folder 99)
      - "To thee, tho' careless of the gift....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 100)
      - "When some proud son of man....", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 101)
        Byron's epitaph on his dog, Boatswain 2 copies
    - Other Papers
      - Artwork, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 102)
        2 cut-paper silhouettes and pencil sketch of mourner weeping over urn
      - Calling cards and ticket (Box 1, Folder 103)
      - "Favola per Carolina mia", n.d. (Box 1, Folder 104)
        Manuscript, corrected In Italian
      - Mottoes for chapters of unidentified work, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 105)
        Manuscript
      - Music, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 106)
        French songs and notation, "Sent from Paris by Miss Knollys"
      - Prayers, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 107)
      - Bibliographical information, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 108)